Chapter 2

In a hallway of Hogwarts, a boy stood silent, with the moonlit form of a human standing by his side and that of a serpent before him.

"Hello, my Heir. You have ssaid that you would sseek my Chamber. You may have expected ssome great trialss, ssome tasskss I will sset of you to prove your worth before I grant you my ssecretss."

"I am not sso foolissh ass that. When I look back on my own younger yearss, I ssee nothing in them that could passss any real tesst I might lay now. The purposse of the Chamber iss not to judge my desscendantss; they may judge each other ass they pleasse. The riddle of the Patronuss wass not intended ass a tesst upon you, ssimply ass a ssafeguard againsst otherss who might sseek my ssecretss for themsselvess, or sseek to bury them and hide them forever from my true Heirss."

Well, even if that made Harry feel a bit stupid, it was encouraging from the point of view of Salazar's intelligence that what he had planned as a simple safeguard had tricked Harry for nearly a year.

"The purposse of my Chamber iss ssimply to grant power to my desscendantss, that they may write the future in their image, and thuss in mine. I ssupposse thiss iss sselfissh of me, but you may think what you will. There iss, however, one thing that will be required of you, before you are taken to the Chamber. If you have found the chance to make usse of Parsseltongue, you may have noticed a peculiarity of it."

Harry thought he knew where this was going, and his heart was racing.

"When sspeaking in Parsseltongue, it iss not possssible to lie. Ever. There iss a reasson I choosse the ssnake ass my ssigil. For all that humanss desspisse them, the sspirit of ssnakess iss a sspirit of abssolute honessty - among themsselvess, at leasst."

The voice sounded drier here, somehow more amused, and frighteningly close to that of Professor Quirrell.

"To otherss you may sspeak ass you will, but know that the cursse I have bound you with iss one of complete honessty within the bloodline of Sslytherin. The finesst Occlumenss born cannot tell the sslightesst falssehood in thiss sspeech. And before thiss emisssary leadss you to my Chamber, it will require a ssimple asssurance from you, that you intend no harm to any of my ssecretss, that my Chamber and my Monsster sshall remain untouched by your hand."

Harry had to resist the urge to punch the air.

"I asssure you that I intend..."

The silver serpent cut him off.

"Repeat exactly the wordss of my emisssary. They have been chossen carefully to allow no trickss of wording, and I advise you follow this example in any future dealings in this tongue."

The ssnake sspoke, and Harry echoed.

"I currently intend no actionss towardss the Chamber of Ssecretss or towardss anything I might find there that could in any way harm the ability of the Chamber to convey its ssecretss to ssubssequent Heirss of Sslytherin, and I do not anticipate my intentionss changing at any point in the future."

"Place your hand upon me and do not let go," hissed the silvery form of Draco's Patronus, and Harry complied. Then the snake hissed, raised its head, flickered its tongue as if tasting the air, and then turned as a Patronus about to depart.

And, as it did, Harry followed.

The Chamber of Secrets, disappointingly enough, didn't look like anything special - it simply looked like an empty classroom. There was even a door, which Harry had peered out of - it seemed to lead to a disused hallway.

"There are two final thingss I am to ssay to you. Firsst, you may come and go to thiss Chamber in future. To depart, ssimply leave by that door." The snake flicked its head towards the door. "You will not be able to find the door again in future; if you wissh to come again, you musst call me again and again sswear that you intend no harm. No otherss may be brought to thiss Chamber - they cannot find this door from within Hogwartss, even if you help them, and I will not bear them. Sslytherin'ss Monsster will arrive sshortly to begin your training, young Heir. Everything in this Chamber worth your attention or use liess with it; there is nothing elsse you need do while waiting, take the time to resst."

The serpent turned again, and vanished, but Harry remained, staring into one corner of the room, with a chill running down his spine.

In the corner of the Chamber, surrounded by the dust of years, lay a Penseive. And before it there lay a note.

Harry stared down at the note, but he knew, somehow, what he would see, even before he saw the signature at the bottom.

Yours,

T. M. Riddle.

Hello, fellow Heir.

In the spirit of our founder, Salazar Slytherin, I have left you a gift too. Mine, alas, is rather less useful than his, but we do what we can.

I leave you this empty, useless Chamber, whose Monster has been slain and whose treasures have been taken. If you are interested in how it was done, I suggest you consult the Penseive next to this note.

I should not be leaving this note at all, of course, much less the Penseive - it violates my Rules Twelve, Fifteen, Twenty-Four, and even Rule One - but I find myself simply unable to resist. In any case, should you plan to take vengeance on me for depriving you of your inheritance, I strongly urge you to first consult the Penseive and then consider the likely outcome of such an attempt.

While I will understand if you do not trust me given the circumstances, I give you my oath that the Penseive is safe to consult, and most certainly safer to consult than not.

Yours,

T. M. Riddle

Chapter 5

The appointed hour had almost arrived.

Harry lowered his wand and paused, taking a moment to control his breathing. He was standing by the Hogwarts Lake, in as exposed a location as he could manage. The rest of Hogwarts had been evacuated to what Harry had claimed would be a safe distance (though the idea of that seemed almost laughable to him). He'd also sent a Patronus Charm to Professor Quirrell, just to make sure Quirrel knew where he was, since Professor Quirrell failing to show up would be...a significant disaster.

In any case, he needn't have worried. Seven days to the minute from the moment Quirrell had retrieved the Stone, a rapidly approaching form became visible in the sky. Harry hadn't expected Quirrell to bring any Death Eaters along - he wouldn't want to expose any useful minions to the risk of Harry, say, Transfiguring a thin carbon filament through their brains - but the approaching figure seemed to be surrounded by other ones...

As Quirrell descended, Harry had some trouble keeping his voice level.

"I take it the Philosopher's Stone lets you give yourself...additional blood to replace what is lost?"

A laugh, not the dry chuckle of the Defense Professor but the cruel jeer of Lord Voldmort. "Sso you ssee, boy."

The Dark Lord touched down, the grass around him blackening and dying. Around him whirled dozens of concentric circles of blackened wings, burning phoenixes of dark fire beyond count, seeming to scorch the very air even at this distance.

Enough destructive power to level Hogwarts, tear it to the ground, consume it stone by stone until nothing remained save ash.

The Philosopher's Stone was scary.

The mocking voice spoke again, not in Parseltongue this time. (Harry was learning to pay attention to things like that.) "I confess, I was surprised to receive your message."

Harry inclined his head.

"I trust you are about to tell me that you have come up with some scheme so brilliantly clever I have no choice but to surrender?" Faint, hissing laughter. "If sso, boy, would be wisse to ssay sso sswiftly."

The gun was in Quirrell's hand, aimed cleanly at Harry's chest.

Harry wasn't afraid of that. He had a Shield Charm up, and though normally it would take until fifth or sixth year for a student to be able to reliably deflect bullets that rule didn't really apply here.

(For that matter, it would normally take until third or fourth year for a student to be able to even cast a Shield Charm. Again, though, that didn't really apply here).

Professor Quirrell had evidently noticed the Charm. "Interessting. Did not think you would be capable of that magic, boy. I will confesss I am intrigued, but your messsage annoyed me and my patience iss wearing thin. It iss not wisse to annoy Lord Voldemort, child - sspeak now, before you losse the ability."

The Dark Lord seemed confident in his ability to kill Harry even through a Shield Charm his magic couldn't interact with. Not to say that was a stupid belief for him to have - Harry had thought of several ways for a more powerful wizard to kill a less powerful one despite the resonance between their magics. Imperius curses on wizards of intermediate power, who could then kill him for you - though perhaps a less invasive form of mind magic would be necessary, Harry didn't know if the resonance would be carried through an Imperius-ed conduit - were the most obvious one, but there were plenty of others, especially for someone who had read the D&D source books and knew why Conjuration spells bypassed Spell Resistance.

If a spell creates something that is not of its nature magical, that thing can affect even foes that would normally be impervious to magic. When Harry had Finite-d his Transfigured rock inside the troll's throat, the troll hadn't been killed by a spell - it had been killed by the sudden appearance of a simple, non-magical rock in its throat. Similarly, a spell to create nonmagical fire, or to send nonmagical stones or knives flying with great velocity at the target, or to Transfigure a nonmagical nuclear weapon near them, would not be a direct magical interaction, and would not trigger the resonance.

Harry had spent some time over the past few days thinking of all the ways you could use magic to kill someone you couldn't directly affect with magic, for exactly the opposite of the reason you might expect.

"Yess, I have plan. Wissh to tell you one thing firsst, though."

The Dark Lord hissed. "And what might that be?"

"Ssusspect that sshortly you will want to kill me. Wisshed to be clear that it will not work. Even if you are willing to ssacrifice body, even if you sseek to classh your magic with my own to trigger ressonance, you will not be able to kill me here."

The Dark Lord paused, and if those red eyes were human ones Harry could have sworn they would have blinked. Then he smiled, and his voice dripped with contempt.

"Ah, I see. Almost clever, boy...for a first-year student. To have yourself Confunded, or perhaps Legilimized, so that you can threaten me in Parseltongue and mean it. But it is four decades short of the cunning you will need to challenge me, and you do not have four decades. You do not have four minutess. It iss over, boy."

Harry raised his wand, and the Dark Lord laughed. "Come then. The look on your face when you realize will be worth letting you live another few seconds. Cast the mighty spell you think I cannot match, for I wish to see your dismay when you realize it was only a trick you played upon yourself. It would be a pity were such fine cruelty to go to waste."

Harry raised his wand. "Do you see that rock, over there?" He had left his father's rock by the edge of the pond. It seemed like a fitting last use for it.

"Do you sseek to delay me, boy, or iss there point to thiss?"

"Iss point. Watch. And would be wisse to raise sshieldss upon yoursself if not already pressent, sside effectss could be unpleassant elsse." Harry had considered omitting that warning, but on the whole it seemed wiser not to annoy the Dark Lord except where it was necessary.

He was spinning through space, whirling across the solar system faster than any human could imagine travelling...Harry flicked his wand in the direction of the rock and spoke two words.

Chapter 6

Since, by the laws of Relativity, there was no such thing as a single privileged reference frame, that meant there was no such thing as being 'stationary'. An object could be stationary within a frame of reference, or relative to another object. But to bring an object to a halt in one frame of reference was to cause it to move in another one. And that meant...

"Arresto Momentum!"

For a brief time as the shock wave travelled through the air, perhaps the twentieth part of a heartbeat , there was no sound, only a vertical line of fire reaching up into the sky.

Then the sonic boom hit, strong enough at this distance to knock people off their feet, to shatter eardrums, possibly to damage organs through sudden overpressure.

The Boy-Who-Lived and the Dark Lord stood facing one another, as the wind and the fire blasted past the blue shields around them.

One of them was laughing.

The Dark Lord's head was thrown back, and he was laughing. But it wasn't the laugh Harry had expected to hear.

He had heard Professor Quirrell's laugh, and it was a dry and cynical laugh at the stupidity of others.

He had heard the Dark Lord's laugh, and it was a cold and cruel laugh at their suffering.

But this was a different kind of laugh altogether.

Lord Voldemort was happy. Not with a malicious, vindictive glee to have seen others suffer; not with a cynical amusement to have been proved right yet again; but with what seemed like genuine and sincere enjoyment.

Then, just as suddenly, the laughter stopped, and the piercing eyes of the Dark Lord were upon him.

"Interesting, boy. Is this what you spoke of in the threat your Patronus conveyed to me? If sso, I fear it will not be adequate."

"It iss part of the power I have gained, but only a part. Realize that thiss alone iss not ssufficient to truly kill you - even if I ssend rock flying into you at great sspeed, Horcruxess will let you return eassily."

"Good that you realize that. So, if you know that thiss power iss inadequate to your needss, what power iss it that makess you sso confident? What power iss it that let you ssend me ssuch a threat?"

Harry had sent his Patronus to find Lord Voldemort with a message to meet him at this place at this time. Then he had added a phrase in Parseltongue.

"I am not certain what your interesstss are, but regardlesss I can asssure you abssolutely that to sshow up at the appointed place and time will be better for those interesstss than to not arrive."

Harry guessed that sounded like a threat.

Well, it was a threat.

If he had nothing to offer the Dark Lord that would serve as sufficient incentive to change his mind, that was the only other possibility.

And yet...this had seemed like a bad idea.

A really bad idea.

A really really bad idea.

His inner Hufflepuff and Gryffindor had gone on strike at the suggestion of what he was soon going to say, rejecting it completely as a solution. Until...

"Before I ansswer that, I wissh to know what your goalss are."

A hiss. "Foolissh boy, I will not give you tactical information that betterss your possition in fear of-"

"Not sshort-term planss, not implementationss nor tacticss. Long-term goalss. Once you have sshattered all ressistance, once you reign undissputed, what will you do then? If there were no limitss to the power of your magic, what would you do, if you could do anything?"

Every part of Harry was holding their breath.

"And if my ansswer iss not to your liking?"

"Sshould you fail to ansswer, I will asssume your reasson for thiss iss that your goalss are sso evil ass to be worsse than anything I can imagine, and will act accordingly." It might not be a fair thing to say, it actually felt a lot like the argumentative equivalent of taking hostages, but if nothing else Professor Quirrell had definitely broken that rule first.

But the Dark Lord only laughed, and reached inside his cloak, tossed something to land near Harry's feet.

Harry looked down.

It was a biology textbook. A standard high-school textbook, the sort Harry had read entirely in fourth grade and moved on from.

And the sort that Harry had given to Quirrell a few weeks ago.

His conscious mind didn't yet know exactly where this was going, but it felt as if some horrible dark thought were brewing inside him, rising up inexorably...

"Really, Mr. Potter, you should have seen it for yourself. It never fails to amaze me how naive you are about which parts of your knowledge can be dangerous. But this knowledge you already knew for yourself to be dangerous. The fascists, a bunch of very nasty people..." The voice was Professor Quirrell's, but the mockery was Lord Voldemort's. "You have already seen this knowledge used for what you would call evil, and yet you gave it to me anyway. And for that, I thank you, Mr. Potter."

Something terrible and hidden, mysterious and dark...

"After all, I have two favorite things in this world, Mr. Potter. One of them is killing idiots...and the other is finding intelligent people. And until you gave me this book, I never even realized that I could pursue both goals at once."

Harry's fingers were trembling where they rested on the wand. A policy of comprehensive eugenics, implemented by a mind with the power and intelligence of Professor Quirrel behind it, with the sole goal of producing people Lord Voldemort considered worth talking to...

He raised the wand. "No."

"And what do you plan to do about it, boy? You still have not presented me with any threat adequate to change my motivations. You still have not offered me any prize sufficient to turn me aside. Why should I listen to you?"

Harry took a deep breath. "Because I posssesss the power to end you completely, to ssever your chain of existence and leave nothing left, no trace that once you were. I have not done sso already becausse the level of collateral damage would be incredible, but I will do sso if you continue down thiss path."

"And what path would you have me take instead, boy?"

A feeling of loss, of sacrifice, of doors closing, of possibilities forever out of reach... "To arrange this would be difficult, but I feel it should be achievable, using Unbreakable Vows. I wish for us both to sacrifice our magic, sacrifice our lives as wizards, and return to the Muggle world we were born in. You may continue the goals you are currently set upon, and I will continue on mine, but we will continue them with the tools of Muggles. We may meet one another as enemies, somewhere down the road, but we will meet the weapons of Muggles, not with the far greater and more terrible power of wizards."

"Unacceptable. " There was a fury in the voice so cold it seemed to have almost physical force, the word hissed so viciously Harry couldn't even say for sure whether it was in Parseltongue or not. "I will accept no ssuch termss, not from a fool of a firsst-year who hass learned ssome petty trickss and thinkss he hass gained power. You will tell me now, boy, will tell me how it iss you think you can vanquissh me. Then I will demonsstrate to you how your plan iss sspectacularly flawed. Then I will kill you. Then I will find all thosse who you care about, all thosse who are near and dear, and I will sspend an eternity in teaching them the price of your inssolence and your defiance." The face of the Dark Lord was a livid mask of fury, and Harry stepped back reflexively.

"Sso tell me, boy! What iss it, thiss power of yourss? How iss it that you think to besst me?"

Harry didn't say the words out loud, however much he wanted to it wouldn't actually be a good idea to give it away. But it was in his mind in spite of that, something he would never get a better chance to say.

Tell me, Professor...have you ever played Morrowind?

Chapter 8: Omake – Till Death Shall Fall

It seems like the previous chapter didn't make it completely clear that it was the last one, so just to be clearer: this story is over. I do not intend to write any further, partly because I don't actually know what happens next but mostly because I don't think whatever happens next would be as interesting to write about. If you're following this story to see what happens: sorry, you won't find out. I don't even know.

As an apology, have an omake. This is a bizarre theory I came up with for what happened when Voldemort tried to kill Harry at Godric's Hollow. While it has been thoroughly and comprehensively falsified (and wasn't ever really plausible to begin with), I still like it.

The three of them stood there in silence, their minds twisting in doubt and in fear.

They were none of them cowards; some would say that they were among the bravest wizards who had ever lived. Not in the sense that they did not fear Death, for they feared it terribly. Not in the sense that they would charge heedlessly into danger, for they would not. But in the sense that they would never shy away from a task, however far beyond them it might seem. They would not let their little fears master them, they would not turn aside when there was a foe they needed to face.

And yet, there came a point when they looked back on the years of effort they had spent, and looked forwards at the years they had left, and they saw the hand of Death rising inexorable, and they knew that they had not done enough.

In a story, this would have been the darkness just before the dawn. In a story, they would have reached deep inside them for every drop of strength they possessed, and in a moment of glory they would have found their answer.

But to expect that would be foolishness. To find power that they did not already possess would imply that there was some strength they had for some reason been holding back before, some plausible idea or some promising plan that they had not already tried.

And the Brothers Peverell had long ago accepted that they did not live in a story.

But, at length, one of them spoke, and said: "What if we..."

currentDate = 19811031;

membersOfHousePotterLiving = 2;

"Lily, take Harry and go! It's him!" shouted a man's voice. "Go! Run! I'll hold him off!"

Then the other voice spoke, high-pitched like the hiss of a teakettle, like a brand of metal cooled to liquid helium temperatures and laid on every part of the body. And the voice said:

"Avadakedavra."

membersOfHousePotterLiving = 1;

"Not Harry, not Harry, please not Harry!" screamed the woman's voice.

"Step aside, woman!" said the shrill voice of burning cold. "For you I am not come, only the boy."

"Not Harry! Please... have mercy... have mercy..."

"I give you this rare chance to flee," said the shrill voice. "But I will not trouble myself to subdue you, and your death here will not save your child. Step aside, foolish woman, if you have any sense in you at all!"

"Not Harry, please no, take me, kill me instead!"

"Very well," said the voice of death, now sounding coldly amused, "I accept the bargain. Yourself to die, and the child to live. Now drop your wand so that I can murder you."

There was a hideous silence.

Lord Voldemort began to laugh, horrible contemptuous laughter.

And then, at last, Lily Potter's voice shrieked in desperate hate, "Avada ke-"

The lethal voice finished first, the curse rapid and precise.

"Avadakedavra."

A blinding flare of green marked the end of Lily Potter.

And the boy in the crib saw it, the eyes, those two crimson eyes, seeming to glow bright red, to blaze like miniature suns, filling Harry's whole vision as they locked to his own. The wand came up, and the cold voice began, "Ava-"

immediateThreat = True;

pLethal= 0.997;

IF (immediateThreat == True && membersOfHousePotterLiving == 1 && pLethal GREATER THAN engageThreshold ) THEN ...

And, ordinarily, that would have been the end of it. Lord Voldemort was a powerful wizard indeed, a master of the Dark Arts armed with the last lore of Salazar Slytherin. But the wards that protected House Potter had been laid upon their bloodline by the three Brothers Peverell themselves, to ensure the continuation of their line, to ensure the completion of their Quest though it should not come for centuries. And into those wards had been poured magic and lore beyond reckoning, with years of labor from three of the wisest wizards to live in an age when magic was strong, to shield and preserve their descendants until Death should fall. Before them, all the Dark Lord's power was as a child with a schoolboy's Charm against a trained battlemage. Oh, the art of Horcrux was an intriguing one, but it was one that had been thoroughly ravelled by that makers of these wards, and one that it was well within their power to break.

Ordinarily.

But his strength and his lore, his Dark magic and his Horcruxes, were not the only protections upon Lord Voldemort.

membersOfHouseGauntRemaining = 1;